{"category":"food_and_drink","correctAnswer":"Shaped pasta","incorrectAnswers":["Soup pasta","Stuffed pasta","Ribbon pasta"],"question":"What type of pasta is cavatelli?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"music","correctAnswer":"ABBA","incorrectAnswers":["In Flames","HammerFall","Katatonia"],"question":"Which band includes 'Anni-Frid Lyngstad'?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Russia","incorrectAnswers":["Bhutan","North Korea","Myanmar"],"question":"Which of these countries borders Mongolia?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"sport_and_leisure","correctAnswer":"Football","incorrectAnswers":["Swimming","Hockey","Motor racing"],"question":"With which sport is Eusebio associated?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"\"Is it safe?\"","incorrectAnswers":["\"Wait a minute, wait a minute. You ain't heard nothin' yet!\"","\"Tell 'em to go out there with all they got and win just one for the Gipper.\"","\"That’s a bingo!\""],"question":"Which of these quotes is from the film 'Marathon Man'?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Lebanon","incorrectAnswers":["Jordan","Oman","Iran"],"question":"Where would you find the city of Beirut?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Guatemala","incorrectAnswers":["Bosnia & Herzegovina","Northern Ireland","Germany"],"question":"In which country would you find Tikal National Park?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"1998","incorrectAnswers":["1995","2001","2004"],"question":"The Big Lebowski was released in which year?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"American Beauty","incorrectAnswers":["The Cider House Rules","The Green Mile","The Insider"],"question":"Which film won the Academy Award for Best Picture in 1999?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"society_and_culture","correctAnswer":"Manscaping","incorrectAnswers":["Bodyculture","Topihairy","Guydening"],"question":"What is the slang term for removing body hair from men?","difficulty":"easy"},{"category":"music","correctAnswer":"George Harrison","incorrectAnswers":["John Lennon","Paul McCartney","Ringo Starr"],"question":"Who was the first Beatle to have a solo No 1 hit?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"Animal House","incorrectAnswers":["The Breakfast Club","Fast Times at Ridgemont High","The Karate Kid"],"question":"Which 1978 movie features the line 'It was the Deltas against the rules... the rules lost!'?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"sport_and_leisure","correctAnswer":"Athletics","incorrectAnswers":["Rugby Union","Ice Hockey","Cycling"],"question":"With which sport is Hicham El Guerrouj associated?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"A bullet","incorrectAnswers":["A space rocket","A submarine","A pen"],"question":"What type of object does the title of the movie 'Full Metal Jacket' refer to?","difficulty":"easy"},{"category":"science","correctAnswer":"The relationship of organisms to each other and to their environment","incorrectAnswers":["Bacteria","Wounds and injuries caused by accidents","Psychotropic drugs"],"question":"What is Bioecology the study of?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"science","correctAnswer":"Veins","incorrectAnswers":["Skin","Hair","Liver"],"question":"What part of the body is the medical field of phlebology concerned with?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"science","correctAnswer":"Osteopath","incorrectAnswers":["Podiatrist","Chiropractor","Oncologist"],"question":"What is the name given to a bone specialist?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"music","correctAnswer":"George Michael","incorrectAnswers":["Paul McCartney","Beyoncé","Gary Barlow"],"question":"Whose debut solo album was called Faith?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"The Hudson ","incorrectAnswers":["The Jackson","The Mississippi","The Rio Grande"],"question":"On which River does the City of New York stand?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"arts_and_literature","correctAnswer":"Stenciling","incorrectAnswers":["Stamping","Collaging","Embossing"],"question":"What is a method of producing images or letters by painting over holes cut in a covering surface?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"arts_and_literature","correctAnswer":"Othello","incorrectAnswers":["Macbeth","Hamlet","Romeo and Juliet"],"question":"What Shakespearean tragedy features Roderigo and Iago at the start of the play?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Île de la Cité","incorrectAnswers":["Île de Ré","le-de-Paris","Île-de-France"],"question":"What is the name of the island that is considered the historic center of Paris and is surrounded by the River Seine?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"science","correctAnswer":"The kidneys","incorrectAnswers":["Heat","Death","Sacred texts"],"question":"What is Nephrology the study of?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Denver","incorrectAnswers":["Chicago","Philadelphia","San Francisco"],"question":"What is the capital of Colorado? ","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"science","correctAnswer":"Hydrogen","incorrectAnswers":["Oxygen","Helium","Carbon"],"question":"Which chemical has the atomic number one?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"history","correctAnswer":"1997","incorrectAnswers":["1982","1967","1952"],"question":"In which year did the UK return Hong Kong sovereignty to China?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"arts_and_literature","correctAnswer":"Juliet","incorrectAnswers":["Romeo","Mercutio","Tybalt"],"question":"In \"Romeo and Juliet\", who said \"I have a faint cold, fear thrills through my veins\"?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"food_and_drink","correctAnswer":"Nectarine ","incorrectAnswers":["Agave","Guava","Lychee"],"question":"Which fruit is a cross between a peach and a plum?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"food_and_drink","correctAnswer":"Gin","incorrectAnswers":["Rum","Brandy","Vodka"],"question":"According to some, 'Dutch courage' in battle came from the over consumption of what ?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"science","correctAnswer":"James Watt","incorrectAnswers":["Benjamin Franklin","Eli Whitney","Marcus Steam"],"question":"Who Invented The Steam Engine?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"science","correctAnswer":"ancient multicelled plants","incorrectAnswers":["eggs","the study, especially statistical, of elections","viruses"],"question":"What is Paleophytology the study of?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"Shakespeare in Love","incorrectAnswers":["Elizabeth","Life Is Beautiful","Saving Private Ryan"],"question":"Which film won the Academy Award for Best Picture in 1998?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"1981","incorrectAnswers":["1976","1986","1991"],"question":"In which year was Raiders of the Lost Ark released?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"arts_and_literature","correctAnswer":"Johannes V. Jensen","incorrectAnswers":["Hans Christian Andersen","Søren Kierkegaard","Agatha Christie"],"question":"Which author wrote 'Digte'?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"history","correctAnswer":"Nero","incorrectAnswers":["Augustus","Justinian","Hadrian"],"question":"Which Roman emperor followed Claudius?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"The Truman Show","incorrectAnswers":["Eternal Sunshine of the Spotless Mind","Dead Poet's Society","The Shawshank Redemption"],"question":"Which movie features the quote 'Good morning! And in case I don't see you, good afternoon, good evening, and good night!'?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"music","correctAnswer":"Paul Simon","incorrectAnswers":["Bob Dylan","Joni Mitchell","Leonard Cohen"],"question":"Which singer-songwriter's lyrics include 'People talking without speaking...people writing songs that voices never share'?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"arts_and_literature","correctAnswer":"‎Rembrandt van Rijn","incorrectAnswers":["Cassius Marcellus Coolidge","Raphael","Paul Cézanne"],"question":"Which artist painted \"Night Watch\"","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"society_and_culture","correctAnswer":"St. Augustine","incorrectAnswers":["Spinoza","Socrates","Kant"],"question":"Which philosopher famously said 'We are too weak to discover the truth by reason alone'?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Senegal","incorrectAnswers":["Tunisia","Tanzania","Kenya"],"question":"In which country is the city of Dakar?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"Leonardo DiCaprio","incorrectAnswers":["Ralph Fiennes","Brian Cox","Kiefer Sutherland"],"question":"Which actor has starred in films including Inception and The Revenant?","difficulty":"easy"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"Who Framed Roger Rabbit","incorrectAnswers":["The Little Mermaid","Beauty and the Beast","Space Jam"],"question":"In which 1988 animated film did Jessica Rabbit appear?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Jamaica","incorrectAnswers":["Morocco","Gabon","Spain"],"question":"Which country's flag can be described as 'Black and green triangles divided by a yellow cross.'?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"society_and_culture","correctAnswer":"Hogmanay","incorrectAnswers":["Bangui","Burns Night","Candlemas Day"],"question":"What is New Year's Eve called in Scotland?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"Zendaya","incorrectAnswers":["Elizabeth Olsen","Hayley Atwell","Karen Gillan"],"question":"Which actor plays the role of Michelle \"MJ\" Jones-Watson in the Marvel Cinematic Universe?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"general_knowledge","correctAnswer":"Six of one, half dozen of another","incorrectAnswers":["A penny for your thoughts","A bird in the hand is worth two in the bush","Don't put all your eggs in one basket"],"question":"What is the idiom used to describe a situation where there is little difference between two options or choices?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Ljubljana","incorrectAnswers":["Sarajevo","Yaounde","Reykjavik"],"question":"What is the capital city of Slovenia?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"science","correctAnswer":"A microwave","incorrectAnswers":["A toaster oven","A convection oven","A slow cooker"],"question":"What type of oven did Percy Spencer invent after a magnetron melted his candy bar?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Yamoussoukro","incorrectAnswers":["Male","Bamako","Moroni"],"question":"What is the capital city of Cote d'Ivoire?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"science","correctAnswer":"Apiology","incorrectAnswers":["Entomology","Ornithology","Zoology"],"question":"What is the study of bees called?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"music","correctAnswer":"Woodwind","incorrectAnswers":["Brass","Percussion","Stringed"],"question":"What type of instrument is a fife?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Valletta","incorrectAnswers":["Brazzaville","Sarajevo","Maputo"],"question":"What is the capital city of Malta?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Africa","incorrectAnswers":["South America","Oceania","Europe"],"question":"The country of Togo is on which continent?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"history","correctAnswer":"Yalta Agreement","incorrectAnswers":["Berlin Agreement","Churchill Agreement","Stoeb Agreement"],"question":"Following World War 2, Germany was split into two zones by which agreement?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Poland","incorrectAnswers":["Bulgaria","Lithuania","Latvia"],"question":"Which of these countries borders Ukraine?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"history","correctAnswer":"Babylon","incorrectAnswers":["Atlantis","Jerusalem","Scythia"],"question":"Where were the Hanging Gardens?","difficulty":"easy"},{"category":"music","correctAnswer":"Woodstock","incorrectAnswers":["Lollapalooza","Bonnaroo","Coachella"],"question":"Which 1969 festival was held at Max Yasgur's farm?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"general_knowledge","correctAnswer":"ATM","incorrectAnswers":["Cellular Phone","Microwave Oven","Vacuum Cleaner"],"question":"What was first used in 1967, in Enfield, North London?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"sport_and_leisure","correctAnswer":"Winnipeg Jets","incorrectAnswers":["Winnipeg Padres","Winnipeg Broncos","Winnipeg Penguins"],"question":"Which of these is a hockey team based in Winnipeg?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"society_and_culture","correctAnswer":"Bishop George Berkeley","incorrectAnswers":["Thomas Hobbes","Epictetus","Socrates"],"question":"Which philosopher famously said 'To be is to be perceived' ('Esse est percipi')?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"science","correctAnswer":"8","incorrectAnswers":["2","4","10"],"question":"How Many Bits In A Byte","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"arts_and_literature","correctAnswer":"Catch-22","incorrectAnswers":["To Kill a Mockingbird","Lord of the Flies","1984"],"question":"Which Joseph Heller novel takes place on the island of Pianosa?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"The Hague","incorrectAnswers":["Paris","Prague","Rome"],"question":"Which of these cities is in Netherlands?","difficulty":"easy"},{"category":"science","correctAnswer":"Lungs","incorrectAnswers":["Heart","Skin","Eyes"],"question":"Emphysema Affects Which Part Of The Body?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"arts_and_literature","correctAnswer":"George R. R. Martin","incorrectAnswers":["Stephen King","Jack Vance","Edgar Rice Burroughs"],"question":"Which author wrote 'A Feast for Crows'?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"St. Andrews","incorrectAnswers":["Edinburgh","Glasgow","Inverness"],"question":"Which Scottish town was once a church town but is now a golfing Mecca?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"Anne Hathaway","incorrectAnswers":["Amy Adams","Sally Field","Helen Hunt"],"question":"Who won the 2012 Academy Award for Best Supporting Actress for playing the role of Fantine in Les Misérables?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"society_and_culture","correctAnswer":"To Be Honest","incorrectAnswers":["Two Big Heads","The Best Hope","This Brilliant Human"],"question":"What do the letters 'TBH' mean on internet chats?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"arts_and_literature","correctAnswer":"The End of the Affair","incorrectAnswers":["Love in the Time of Cholera","Master and Commander","All the King's Men"],"question":"Which book contains the character 'Maurice Bendrix'?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Buenos Aires","incorrectAnswers":["Fortaleza","Santiago","Monterrey"],"question":"Which of these cities is in Argentina?","difficulty":"easy"},{"category":"sport_and_leisure","correctAnswer":"10","incorrectAnswers":["7","5","13"],"question":"How Many Cards Are You Dealt In A Game Of Gin Rummy? ","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"music","correctAnswer":"Brass","incorrectAnswers":["Percussion","Stringed","Woodwind"],"question":"What type of instrument is a tuba?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"food_and_drink","correctAnswer":"Farfalle","incorrectAnswers":["Strozzapreti","Fusilli","Orzo"],"question":"Which pasta's name means 'Butterflies'?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"society_and_culture","correctAnswer":"Sound bites","incorrectAnswers":["Catch phrases","Taglines","Mottos"],"question":"What is the name for the quotable, snappy snippets that politicians often use in news broadcasts and speeches?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"history","correctAnswer":"Ehecatl","incorrectAnswers":["Tlaloc","Huitzilopochtli","Quetzalcoatl"],"question":"What was the name of the Aztec god of the wind?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"food_and_drink","correctAnswer":"Plunge into cold water after boiling","incorrectAnswers":["Add a drop of vinegar when boiling","Soak the egg before boiling","Crack the egg a little mid boil"],"question":"How do you prevent a black rim forming round the yolk of a boiled egg?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"food_and_drink","correctAnswer":"Baked Egg","incorrectAnswers":["Fried Rice","Roasted Chilli","Boiled Corn"],"question":"From what is the Mexican dish huevos rancheros made?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Cameroon","incorrectAnswers":["Ukraine","Cuba","Singapore"],"question":"Which of these countries has green on its flag?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"society_and_culture","correctAnswer":"Virtue strives for what is difficult","incorrectAnswers":["Such is life","Tender is the loving mother","Become good through ardor"],"question":"What is the meaning of the Latin phrase 'Tendit in ardua virtus'?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"history","correctAnswer":"The Alps","incorrectAnswers":["The Pindus","The Atlas Mountains","The Urals"],"question":"What mountain range did Hannibal march through in 218 B.C.?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"arts_and_literature","correctAnswer":"Jean Valjean","incorrectAnswers":["Romeo","Hamlet","Yossarian"],"question":"Which iconic literary character spends his life searching for redemption after spending 19 years in prison for stealing a loaf of bread?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"society_and_culture","correctAnswer":"Gemini","incorrectAnswers":["Cancer","Sagittarius","Virgo"],"question":"Which zodiac sign is characterized by a 2-sided personality and frequent mood changes?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"science","correctAnswer":"A sloth","incorrectAnswers":["A rag","A paddling","A sedge"],"question":"What is the word for a group of bears?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"society_and_culture","correctAnswer":"Turkic","incorrectAnswers":["Niger–Congo","Indo-European","Sino-Tibetan"],"question":"The language 'Uyghur' belongs to which language family?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"music","correctAnswer":"Seal","incorrectAnswers":["Madonna","Michael Jackson","Celine Dion"],"question":"Which artist won the Grammy's Record of the Year award in 1995 for the song 'Kiss From A Rose'?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"society_and_culture","correctAnswer":"Fiscal Policy","incorrectAnswers":["Honesty Policy","Tax Policy","Free Market"],"question":"In economics, what is the term for the use of government funds to influence the economy?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"society_and_culture","correctAnswer":"Azul","incorrectAnswers":["Bleu","Azuro","Três"],"question":"In Portuguese, what is the word for for 'blue'?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"general_knowledge","correctAnswer":"Frieze ","incorrectAnswers":["Architrave","Cornice","Fresco"],"question":"What is the name for a band of painted or sculpted decoration, often at the top of a wall?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"history","correctAnswer":"Delaware","incorrectAnswers":["Pennsylvania","New Jersey","New York"],"question":"What was the first US state to join the Union?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"sport_and_leisure","correctAnswer":"Sacramento Kings","incorrectAnswers":["Sacramento Flames","Sacramento Blackhawks","Sacramento Trailblazers"],"question":"Which of these is a basketball team based in Sacramento?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"arts_and_literature","correctAnswer":"Fyodor Dostoyevsky","incorrectAnswers":["Vladimir Nabokov","Leo Tolstoy","Mikhail Bulgakov"],"question":"Which author wrote 'Demons'?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Port Louis","incorrectAnswers":["Vilnius","Castries","Pristina"],"question":"What is the capital city of Mauritius?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"general_knowledge","correctAnswer":"Delta","incorrectAnswers":["Dog","Danube","Dig"],"question":"What word is used in the NATO Phonetic Alphabet for the letter D?","difficulty":"easy"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"Drew Barrymore","incorrectAnswers":["Penélope Cruz","Kirsten Dunst","Charlize Theron"],"question":"Which actress starred in both E.T. the Extra-Terrestrial and Batman Forever?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"science","correctAnswer":"Alexander Fleming","incorrectAnswers":["Robert Fulton","Stephanie Kwolek","James Watt"],"question":"Who discovered Penicillin?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Jewellers","incorrectAnswers":["Butchers","Shoes","Wine"],"question":"What Type Of Shop Predominates On The Ponte Vecchio In Florence?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"science","correctAnswer":"Antifreeze ","incorrectAnswers":["Engine oil","Windscreen wash fluid","Brake fluid"],"question":"Ethylene glycol is frequently used in automobiles. What for? ","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Indochina","incorrectAnswers":["Malay","Malacca","Sunda"],"question":"Cambodia, Laos, and Vietnam are located on what peninsula?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"science","correctAnswer":"Jonas Salk","incorrectAnswers":["Edward Jenner","Alexander Fleming","Louis Pasteur"],"question":"Who developed the polio vaccine?","difficulty":"medium"},